Guide to the Alfred Stieglitz / Georgia O'Keeffe Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, Series IV; 16.8; (31 boxes)
  - COLLECTIONS OF PERSONAL AND STUDY PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Ida O'Keeffe Collection
      Photographs taken at Lake George by Stieglitz and Ida O'Keeffe, and sent to Ida O'Keeffe; gift of Georgia O'Keeffe, 1976.
      - Prints and mounted prints
        - Alfred Stieglitz (1 print), 1923-25 (Box 148, Folder 2746)
        - Ida O'Keeffe (13 prints), 1924-25, n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2747)
        - Ida and Georgia O'Keeffe (2 prints), [1924] (Box 148, Folder 2748)
        - Arnold Rönnebeck (1 print), 1924 (Box 148, Folder 2749)
        - View of the lake, chestnut trees, and still lifes (4 prints), 1923-24, n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2750)
      - Proof prints on printing out paper
        - Alfred (7 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2751)
        - Ida (21 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2752)
        - Georgia (8 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2753)
        - Arnold (3 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2754)
        - Alfred and Georgia (3 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2755)
        - Ida and Georgia (4 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2756)
        - Ida, Georgia, and Arnold (3 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2757)
        - Georgia and Donald Davidson (1 print), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2758)
        - Ida, Georgia, and Donald (5 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2759)
        - Ida and Lizzie Stieglitz [?] (1 print), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2760)
        - Still life [porch mirror] (1 print), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2761)
        - [too faded to tell] (2 prints), [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2762)
        - Envelope that housed proof prints, [1924] (Box 257, Folder 2763)
    - Selma Stieglitz Schubart Collection
      - Equivalents (2 prints) removed from her letters in Series I, 1923, 1936 (Box 148, Folder 2764)
    - Copy Negatives and Prints
      Copies of photographs not in Stieglitz/ O'Keeffe Archive
      Includes copy prints made for the Yale University Library in 1953
      - Alfred Stieglitz (nos. 51, 62-3, 66-7), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2765)
      - Edward Stieglitz (no. 60), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2766)
      - Family members (nos. 54, 61, 64-5, 68), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2767)
      - Bust of Judith by Ezekiel (no. 52), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2768)
      - Race horses toy (no. 59), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2769)
      - Equivalent (no. 57), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2770)
      - Snowy road (no. 56), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2771)
      - Photo-Secession gallery (nos. 53, 55), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2772)
      - Copies of photographs in Stieglitz/ O'Keeffe Archive
        - (Nos. 1-12), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2773)
        - (Nos. 13-14, 16, 20-33, 50, 58), n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2774)
    - Theatrical Portraits
      - Commercial portraits of opera singers, dancers, and actors, 1880-86, n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2775)
        Studio images of Eleanora Duse (2 photographs), Anna de Belocca, Frau. Sachse-Hofmeister, A. Dell Era, Teresina Gepner, Hans [?] Malhart, some with autographs.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS BY STIEGLITZ ASSOCIATES
    - Adams, Ansel
      - Photographs (2 prints) and Christmas card removed from his letters in Series I, 1938-42 (Box 149, Folder 2776)
    - Beckett, Marion
      - Photographs (7 prints) removed from her letter in Series I, 1915 (Box 149, Folder 2777)
    - Brett, Dorothy
      - Photographs (6 prints) of Mabel Luhan's home and the Ranch removed from her letters in Series I, 1929 (Box 149, Folder 2778)
    - Brigman, Anne
      - "The Cleft in the Rock," photogravure, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 2779)
      - Photographs (10 prints) removed from her letters in Series I, 1910-39 (Box 149, Folder 2780)
    - Chabot, Maria
      - Photographs (16 prints) of a camping trip with Georgia O'Keeffe, removed from her letter in Series I, 1944 (Box 149, Folder 2781)
    - Coburn, Alvin Langdon
      - "The White Bridge - Venice" photogravure, 1905 (Box 149, Folder 2782)
    - de Zayas, Marius
      - Caricatures of Photo-Secession members, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 2783)
        Thirteen photographic postcards with images of: Caffin (3); Haviland and de Zayas; Kerfoot (2); Kernochan and Scott; Marin (2); Seeley and Laurvik; Steichen; Stieglitz; White
    - Davison, George
      - Photograph of his houseboat on the Thames, removed from his letter in Series I, 1906 (Box 149, Folder 2784)
    - Eugene, Frank [?]
      - [Woman on bed clutching pillow] photogravure, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 2785)
    - Evans, Frederick
      - York Minster- A Study in Light, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 2786)
    - Gable, Robert
      - Horace Traubel, 1916 (Box 149, Folder 2787)
    - Jones-Doran [Studio]
      - Elizabeth Arden with race horse, ca. 1940 (Box 149, Folder 2788)
    - Kühn, Heinrich
      - Photographs (2 prints) of his home and family removed from his letters in Series I, 1906 (Box 149, Folder 2789)
    - Maurer, Oscar
      - Photograph of his studio removed from his letter in Series I, 1908 Feb 15 (Box 149, Folder 2790)
    - Rhoades, Katharine
      - Photographs (14 prints) removed from her letters in Series I, 1915-22 (Box 149, Folder 2791)
    - Rodakiewicz, Henwar
      - Negatives (31) removed from his letters in Series I, 1938, 1944 (Box 149, Folder 2792)
    - Rönnebeck, Arnold
      - Photographs (10 prints) removed from his letters in Series I, 1925-26 (Box 149, Folder 2793)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J.
      - "Sunset - Cape Split" (with crashing waves on verso), n.d. (Box 149, Folder 2794)
    - Steichen, Edward
      - Edward Stieglitz, [1904] (Box 149, Folder 2795)
      - Katharine Rhoades, ca. 1920 (Box 149, Folder 2796)
      - Photographs (7 prints) of the interior of his home and studio, Paris, and one photograph of his daughters, 1906 Dec (Box 149, Folder 2797)
    - Strand, Paul
      - 291 Fifth Avenue, [1917] (Box 150, Folder 2798)
      - "Marin at work, Southwest", 1930 (Box 150, Folder 2799)
      - "Marin starting a watercolor, Southwest", 1930 (Box 150, Folder 2800)
      - Francis Picabia, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 2801)
      - Rocks, Maine Coast (in original frame from An American Place), 1928 (Box Art, Folder 2802)
        Gift of Paul Rosenfeld
    - White, Clarence
      - Emmy and Kitty Stieglitz, ca. 1899 (Box 150, Folder 2803)
    - White, Clarence and Alfred Stieglitz
      - "Torso," photogravure, [1909] (Box 150, Folder 2804)
        Bequest of Francis Hyde Bangs
    - Zorach, William
      - Photograph of the artist and his family on a camping trip in Yosemite removed from his letter in Series I, 1920 (Box 150, Folder 2805)
    - Unidentified photographer
      - Miss Landon Rives (Box 150, Folder 2806)
      - Photographs (2 prints) of Charles Demuth removed from his letters in Series I, 1922, 1926 (Box 150, Folder 2807)
      - Photographs (4 prints) of Marsden Hartley, and bust of Hartley by Rönnebeck, removed from his letters in Series I, 1923-25 (Box 150, Folder 2808)
      - Miscellaneous portraits, 1941, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 2809)
        Includes Constantin Brancusi, Eliot Porter, John Marin and Arthur B. Carles
      - Photo-Secession silhouette booklet, 1904 (Box 150, Folder 2810)
        Includes autographed photo- silhouettes of Stieglitz, Kasebier, Steichen, Coburn, Keiley, Strauss, Boursault, and Kerfoot; some reproduced in Camera Work No. 8 (1904)
  - EXHIBITION INSTALLATION PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Photo-Secession Gallery
      - "Viennese and German Photographers" (3 views), 1906 (Box 151, Folder 2811)
    - An American Place
      - Ansel Adams exhibition (5 views), 1936 (Box 151, Folder 2812)
      - "Beginnings and Landmarks: 291, 1905-1917" (12 views), 1937 (Box 151, Folder 2813)
    - Museum of Modern Art
      - "John Marin: Watercolors, Oil Paintings, Etchings" (11 views), 1936 (Box 151, Folder 2814)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art
      - "History of an American: Alfred Stieglitz: 291 and After" (13 views), 1944 (Box 151, Folder 2815)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art
      - John Marin exhibition (1 view), n.d. (Box 151, Folder 2816)
- Alfred Stieglitz: Awards, 1887-1937, n.d.; Series V; 0.4; (1 box)
  The series contains medals won by Stieglitz in photographic competitions, including those awarded to the Photochrome Engraving Company. Several remain unidentified and may include some awarded to the Photo-Secession group. Descriptions given below are based on inscriptions and dates that appear on the medals. The awards are arranged alphabetically by the name of the granting organization.
  - REFERENCE PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Reference photographs of medals in Box 152, folders 2817-2866 (Box 151A)
  - AMATEUR FOTOGRAFEN VEREENIGING AMSTERDAM
    - Internationale Fotografie Tentoonstelling Amsterdam, 1895 Sep (Box 152, Folder 2817)
  - AMATEUR PHOTOGRAPHER
    - Holiday Work Competition, 1887 (Box 152, Folder 2818)
    - Home Portraiture Competition, 1889 (Box 152, Folder 2819)
    - Prize Tour Competition, 1889 (Box 152, Folder 2820)
    - Lantern Slide Competition, 1892 (Box 152, Folder 2821)
    - Photography at Home, 1892 (Box 152, Folder 2822)
    - Lantern Slide Competition, 1893 (Box 152, Folder 2823)
  - AMERICAN INSTITUTE NEW-YORK
    - Medal of Excellence for Landscapes, Exhibition Society of Amateur Photographers of New York, 1891 (Box 152, Folder 2824)
    - Medal of Merit to Photochrome Engraving Co. for Photochrome Engravings, 1891 (Box 152, Folder 2825)
    - Medal of Superiority for "Portrait of Professor W", 1898 (Box 152, Folder 2826)
    - Special Medal for Slides, 1st Prize Champion Class, 1898 (Box 152, Folder 2827)
    - Special Medal for "Katwyk Dunes", 1898 (Box 152, Folder 2828)
  - BOROUGH OF NOTTINGHAM, ART GALLERY
    - Success in Art, Awarded by the Committee of the Art Museum, 1888 (Box 152, Folder 2829)
  - BOSTON CAMERA CLUB
    - For Excellence in Photographic Art, 1892 (Box 152, Folder 2830)
  - CAMERA-KLUB, WIEN
    - [Medal], 1898 (Box 152, Folder 2831)
  - COLLEGE OF THE CITY OF NEW YORK ALUMNI ASSOCIATION
    - Townsend Harris Medal for Notable Achievement, 1937 (Box 152, Folder 2832)
  - CLUB DER AMATEUR PHOTOGRAPHEN WIEN
    - Ehrenpreis, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2833)
  - ERZHERZOG FERDINAND IV. GROSSHERZOG VON TOSCANA
    - Ehrenpreis für Hervorragende Leistungen auf dem Gebiete der Photographie (Box 152, Folder 2834)
  - ESPOZIZIONE RIUNITE MILANO
    - Espozizione Internazionale de Fotografia, 1894 (Box 152, Folder 2835)
  - GLASGOW AND WEST OF SCOTLAND
    Glasgow and West of Scotland Amateur Photographic Association
    - To the Photochrome Engraving Company, 1891 (Box 152, Folder 2836)
  - L'EFFORT, BRUXELLES
    - For participation in salon, 1903 (Box 152, Folder 2837)
  - MAGYAR AMATEUR-FOTOGRAFIAI KIáLLITáS BUDAPESTEN
    - Magyarorszagi Kárpát-Egyesület Budapesti Osztálya, 1890 (Box 152, Folder 2838)
  - MUNICIPAL ART GALLERY, LEEDS
    - To the Photochrome Engraving Company for Photochromography, 1891 (Box 152, Folder 2839)
  - THE NATURALISTS' RECORD
    - For Six Prints on the Pizzighelli Platina Direct Printing Paper, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2840)
  - PHOTO-CLUB DE PARIS
    - [Medal], 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2841)
    - Salon, 1902 (Box 152, Folder 2842)
  - PHOTOGRAPHIC SOCIETY OF INDIA
    - [Medal], 1898 (Box 152, Folder 2843)
    - 11th International Exhibition, Calcutta, 1901 (Box 152, Folder 2844)
  - PHOTOGRAPHY
    - Lantern Slides Portraiture, 1892 (Box 152, Folder 2845)
    - Lantern Slides Genre, 1892 (Box 152, Folder 2846)
  - ROYAL PHOTOGRAPHIC SOCIETY
    - [Medal], 1899 (Box 152, Folder 2847)
  - ROYTON PARISH CHURCH OF ST. PAUL
    - Photographic Exhibition, Restoration Aid Committee, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2848)
  - STANLEY SHOW, PHOTOGRAPHIC SECTION
    - For Genre, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2849)
  - TORONTO CAMERA CLUB
    - For Architecture, 1896 (Box 152, Folder 2850)
    - For Genre, 1896 (Box 152, Folder 2851)
    - For Landscape, 1896 (Box 152, Folder 2852)
    - For Marine, 1896 (Box 152, Folder 2853)
    - For Portraits, 1896 (Box 152, Folder 2854)
    - For Architecture, 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2855)
    - For Interior, 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2856)
    - For Genre, 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2857)
    - For Marine, 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2858)
    - For Portraits, 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2859)
    - For Slides, 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2860)
    - [Medal, award unknown], n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2861-2862)
  - VENTNOR AND BONCHURCH
    Ventnor and Bonchurch Literary and Scientific Institution Photographic Exhibition
    - [Medal], 1891 (Box 152, Folder 2863)
  - WIENER PHOTO-KLUB
    - Als Anerkennung für Verdienstvolle Leistungen, 1904 (Box 152, Folder 2864)
  - UNIDENTIFIED INSTITUTIONS/ORGANIZATIONS
    - Photographic Exhibition, 1894 (Box 152, Folder 2865)
    - NCC '95, 1895 (Box 152, Folder 2866)
- Alfred Stieglitz: Works of Art, 1876-1944; Series VI; 15; (9 boxes) + 9 framed works
  The series is arranged in two subseries: Works by Stieglitz Contemporaries; and Works by Children. Works in the first subseries are listed by artist in alphabetical sequences according to their storage arrangements. Framed pieces which are either not boxed (and are stored with other framed objects in the library's art collections, designated ArtS in place of a box number) or have special boxes to hold them appear first. Second listed are all works which are matted to 16 x 20 inches, and third are works which are matted to 20 x 24 inches, followed by the Pamela Coleman Smith paintings. Works by Children end the series.
  - WORKS BY STIEGLITZ'S CONTEMPORARIES
    - Chase, William Merritt
      - Alfred Stieglitz, oil on canvas, framed, 1905 (Box Art, Folder 2867)
    - Demuth, Charles
      - "Poster Portrait: Dove," poster paint on pressed-paper board, framed, 1924 (Box Art, Folder 2868)
      - "Poster Portrait: Duncan," poster paint on pressed-paper board, framed, 1924-25 (Box Art, Folder 2869)
      - Poster Portrait: Marin," poster paint on pressed-paper board, framed, 1926 (Box Art, Folder 2870)
      - "Poster Portrait: O'Keeffe," poster paint on pressed-paper board, framed, 1923-24 (Box 153, Folder 2871)
    - Encke, Fedor
      - Alfred Stieglitz, oil on canvas, 1877 Dec (Box 154, Folder 2872)
      - Alfred Stieglitz, oil on canvas, framed, 1884 Aug 31 (Box Art, Folder 2873)
    - Hasemann, Wilhelm
      - Alfred Stieglitz, watercolor on paper, framed, 1882 (Box 155, Folder 2874)
    - James, Rebecca Salsbury Strand
      - "Edge of the Campo Santo," reverse painting on glass, framed (Box Art, Folder 2875)
        Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Paul Strand, 1966
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia
      - "Pink Roses," pastel, framed, 1934 (Box Art, Folder 2876)
        Bequest of Louise Thörök, 1969
    - Rauth, Otto
      - Alfred Stieglitz, pastel on paper, framed (Box Art, Folder 2877)
    - Ray, Man
      - Alfred Stieglitz, oil on canvas, framed, 1913 (Box Art, Folder 2878)
    - Covarrubias, Miguel
      - Alfred Stieglitz, watercolor on paper, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2879)
    - de Zayas, Marius
      - [Caricature, possibly Edward Steichen] ink on paper, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2880)
    - Dove, William
      - Untitled [submarine?], watercolor on paper, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2881)
    - Encke, Erdmann
      - Alfred Stieglitz [cut paper silhouette], ink on paper, 1882 Nov 14 (Box 156, Folder 2882)
    - Enters, Angna
      - "Alfred Stieglitz: the white line in black" [two versions], ink on paper, ca. 1927 (Box 156, Folder 2883)
      - "Boy Cardinal," print, 1939 (Box 156, Folder 2884)
    - Gerson, Julius
      - [Letters to Stieglitz], watercolor and ink on paper, [1877] (Box 156, Folder 2885)
    - Higgins, Eugene
      - [Woman sitting in doorway], two etchings (Box 156, Folder 2886)
    - Hill, David Octavius
      - [Harbor scene with landscape on verso], crayon and pencil on paper (Box 156, Folder 2887)
        With accompanying note from Elizabeth Sharp to Joseph Keiley, July 1911
    - Lewis, Allen
      - [Christmas greeting for Paul Haviland], etching, 1911 (Box 156, Folder 2888)
        See also: Box 24, folder 555
    - Marin, John
      - Wall Street, pencil on paper, 1905 (Box 156, Folder 2889)
        Gift of E.L Sampfer
      - Alfred Stieglitz, crayon and watercolor on paper, mounted in frame, 1935 (Box 156, Folder 2890)
      - Self-portrait, crayon and watercolor on paper, framed, 1938 (Box 157, Folder 2891)
    - Nolan, John Baptist
      - [Impressions of a visit to 291], ink and pencil on paper, 1915 Oct 24 (Box 157, Folder 2892)
    - O'Brien, Frances
      - Alfred Stieglitz, crayon on paper, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2893)
        Gift of Frances O'Brien, 1968
      - Alfred Stieglitz, crayon on paper, 1944 (Box 157, Folder 2894)
    - Picabia, Francis
      - "New York," ink and pencil on paper, [1913] (Box 157, Folder 2895)
    - Ray, Man
      - "Camera Work," ink on paper, [1912] (Box 157, Folder 2896)
    - Samberger, Leo
      - Fritz Goetz (photograph), n.d. (Box 157, Folder 2897)
    - Weber, Max
      - [Design for exhibition poster], ink and pencil on paper, 1911 (Box 157, Folder 2898)
      - Sketch of Mr. Montross, pencil on paper 1910 (Box 157, Folder 2899)
      - Still life sketch [demonstration for Kitty Stieglitz's art lesson], watercolor on paper, 1910 (Box 157, Folder 2900)
    - Unidentified artists
      - Georgia O'Keeffe, pencil on paper, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 2901)
      - Alfred Stieglitz, pencil on paper, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 2902)
      - Edward Stieglitz, pencil on paper, 1901 Mar (Box 157, Folder 2903)
    - Blum, Robert F.
      - [Venetian scene], watercolor on paper, framed, 1881 (Box 158, Folder 2904)
    - Dove, Arthur
      - "Pen and Razor Blade," collage of metal, paper, crayon, ink, and paint on paper, 1925 (Box 158, Folder 2905)
    - Einstein, William
      - "Alfred Stieglitz and his women," ink on paper, ca. 1936 (Box 158, Folder 2906)
    - Keppler, Joseph
      - "Offenbach," photoengraving, 1876 (Box 158, Folder 2907)
    - Simonson, Lee
      - "Marsden [Hartley] Adopts Germany!," watercolor on paper, 1913 (Box 158, Folder 2908)
    - Smith, Pamela Colman
      - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 158, Folder 2909)
      - [Five exhibition mats previously removed from her paintings], [1907] (Box 158, Folder 2910)
      - "The Blue Cat," watercolor on paper board, 1907 (Box 159, Folder 2911)
      - "A Dirge," ink and pencil on paper, 1907 (Box 159, Folder 2912)
      - [Facing a mosque], watercolor on paper, n.d. (Box 159, Folder 2913)
      - "Overture, Manfred - Schumann," watercolor on paper board, 1907 (Box 159, Folder 2914)
      - "Red Cloak," watercolor and pencil on paper board, 1908 (Box 159, Folder 2915)
      - [Sea creatures], watercolor on paper, n.d. (Box 159, Folder 2916)
      - "Sketch for Glass," watercolor and ink on paper, 1908 (Box 159, Folder 2917)
      - "Sonata in F Major (for Violin and Piano) - Mozart," Second Series Duet, watercolor on paper, 1907 (Box 159, Folder 2918)
      - "Sonata No. 11 - Beethoven," watercolor on paper board, 1907 (Box 159, Folder 2919)
      - "Time," watercolor and pencil on paper board (Box 159, Folder 2920)
      - [Untitled, possibly exhibition poster from 291 street signboard], ink and watercolor on paper, [1907] (Box 159, Folder 2921)
  - WORK BY CHILDREN
    - Stearns, Katherine ("Kitty") Stieglitz
      - "Still Life No. 1," tempera on paper, 1910 (Box 160, Folder 2922)
      - "Still Life No. 2," tempera on paper (in original George Of frame), 1910 (Box 160, Folder 2923)
      - [Five still life paintings], watercolor and tempera on paper, 1910 (Box 160, Folder 2924)
      - [Seven still life paintings attributed to Kitty Stieglitz], watercolor and tempera on paper, [1910] (Box 160, Folder 2925)
      - [Four landscape paintings attributed to Kitty Stieglitz], watercolor and tempera on paper], 1910, n.d. (Box 160, Folder 2926)
    - Boyle, Kay
      - [Still life], watercolor and ink on paper, 1912 (Box 161, Folder 2927)
    - Cromwell, Georgia Engelhard
      - [Three drawings], pencil and crayon on paper, 1913, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 2928)
    - Unknown artist
      - [Exhibition poster from 291 street signboard], crayon and ink on paper, [1912] (Box 161, Folder 2929)
      - [Two drawings in original exhibition mats], crayon on paper, [1912] (Box 161, Folder 2930)
      - [Two paintings], tempera on paper, 1917, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 2931)
      - [Four drawings], mixed media, n.d. (Box 161, Folder 2932)
        Includes work by Ben Brisman, Alice Campbell, and Janet
- Alfred Stieglitz: Art Collection Notebooks, 1951; Series VII; 16.25; (15 boxes)
  The series is arranged in two sets: the first has worksheets and photographs filed alphabetically by artist (and then chronologically within); the second set of worksheets and photographs are filed by the institution which received the works. Please note: The photographs in this series are to be used for study purposes only and will not be duplicated by the library.
  - Set One: Artists
    - African Sculpture; Brancusi, Constantin; Cezanne, Paul; Cros, Henri; Davies, Arthur B.; Demuth, Charles (Box 162)
    - de Zayas, Marius; Dove, Arthur (Box 163)
    - Duncan, Charles; Gag, Wanda; Grosz, George; Hartley, Marsden; Hugue, Manuel (Manolo) (Box 164)
    - Kandinsky, Wassily; Karfiol, Bernard; Kopman, Benjamin; Lachaise, Gaston; Macdonald-Wright, Stanton; Manolo (Box 165)
      See: Hugue
    - Marin, John: through 1914
    - Marin, John: from 1915 (Box 166)
    - Matisse, Henri; Maurer, Alfred; Miller, Kenneth Hayes; Nadelman, Elie; O'Keeffe, Georgia; Pascin, Jules; Picabia, Francis; Picasso, Pablo (Box 167)
    - Renoir, Auguste; Rivera, Diego; Rodin, Auguste; Severini, Gino; Sheeler, Charles; Signac, Paul; Steinlen, Theophile Alexandre; Sterne, Maurice; Stettheimer, Florine; Toulouse Lautrec, Henri de; Walkowitz, Abraham (Box 168)
  - Set Two: Institutions
    - Art Institute of Chicago: American artists (Box 169)
    - Art Institute of Chicago: foreign artists (Box 170)
    - Fisk University: American artists (Box 171)
    - Fisk University: foreign artists (Box 172)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art: American artists (Box 173)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art: American artists (Box 174)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art: foreign artists (Box 175)
    - National Gallery of Art Philadelphia Museum of Art (Box 176)
- Georgia O'Keeffe: Correspondence, 1907-86; Series VIII; 24.2; (58 boxes)
  The series is arranged in four subseries: Personal and Business Correspondence; Subject Files; Fan Mail; and Rights and Reproductions Correspondence
  - PERSONAL AND BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1958-85, n.d. (Box 177, Folder 2933-2934)
    - A. Colish, Inc., 1975-85, n.d. (Box 177, Folder 2935)
    - A. S. Barnes and Company, Inc., 1966 Nov 25 (Box 177, Folder 2936)
    - A. Watkins, Inc., 1968 Feb 19 (Box 177, Folder 2937)
    - Abiquiu Elementary School, 1983 (Box 177, Folder 2938)
      See also: Española Municipal Schools, Box 190, folder 3221
    - ACA Galleries, 1972-83, n.d. (Box 177, Folder 2939)
    - Ackerman, Phyllis, 1950-65, n.d. (Box 177, Folder 2940)
    - Acosta, Mercedes de, 1962 Aug 5 (Box 177, Folder 2941)
      See also: Witter Bynner, Box 182, folder 3047
    - Adams, Ansel and Virginia, 1938-85, n.d. (Box 177, Folder 2942-2944)
      See also: KQED, Box 182, folder 3407
      See also: Godfrey Rockefeller, Box 211, folder 3700
    - Adams, Mary; Adams, Clinton, 1964-81 (Box 177, Folder 2945)
    - Adato, Perry Miller
      See: WNET/13, Box 219, folders 3918-3919
    - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1968-85 (Box 177, Folder 2946)
    - Allen, M. Carol, 1949, 1967 (Box 177, Folder 2947)
    - Allen, Lawrence
      See: The Downtown Gallery, Box 189, folders 3188-3190
    - Allen, Mary, 1970-85 (Box 177, Folder 2948)
    - Amarillo Art Center Association, 1982-85 (Box 177, Folder 2949)
    - Amarillo Public Schools, 1914 Sep 1 (Box 177, Folder 2950)
    - America Illustrated, 1974-75 (Box 177, Folder 2951)
      Includes: draft of article on O'Keeffe